An Inventory of the White House Conference on Child Health and Protection Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Committee on Socially Handicapped Dependency and Neglect, Section IVC-1
  - Records relating to health programs in institutions, 1930. (Folder 56: 9)
    Includes correspondence, lists of clinics and institutions, memorandum, notes, and questionnaire
- Committee on the Handicapped, Section IV
  - C. C. Carstens, 1929-1930. (Folder 56: 10)
  - Minutes of meeting of the committee chairman and research secretaries, Washington, D.C, 1930 May 12 (Folder 56: 11)
- Committee on Physically and Mentally Handicapped, Section IVB, undated.
  Special report
- Committee on National, State and Local Organizations for the Handicapped, Section IVA (Folder 56: 12)
  - General, 1930. (Folder 56: 13)
    Correspondence, minutes of meeting, and report
  - Children's Bureau, 1930. (Folder 56: 14)
    A letter to Homer Folks from Owen R. Lovejoy, and minutes of meeting
- Committee on Public Relations, Section V, 1929-1930. (Folder 56: 15)
- Committee on Publications, 1930. (Folder 56: 16)
- Committee on Socially Handicapped Dependency and Neglect, Section IVC-1, Day nurseries, 1930-1931. (Box-folder 57: 1)
  Correspondence, list of nursery schools and day nurseries by state, notes, outline of materials to be used for the report, and short report
- Committee II on Methods of Care for Children Elsewhere than in Own Home
  - Miscellany, 1929-1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 2)
    Includes clipping, correspondence, memoranda, outline of report and genetic study of infancy, rules set for health supervision for child caring institutions and agencies, and health education program for children's institutions
  - Subcommittee on legal processes involved, etc., 1927-1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 3)
    Article and correspondence
- Committee III on Neglect
  - Minutes of meetings, 1930. (Folder 57: 4-5)
  - Theodore A. Lothrop, 1929-1931. (Folder 57: 6)
    Correspondence and memoranda
  - Report, 1930. (Folder 57: 7-8)
    Includes comments on the report, correspondence, statement of report and findings, summary of questionnaires, and related materials
  - Correspondence relating to animal protective work, 1928-1930. (Folder 57: 9-10)
    Includes memoranda, printed matter, report on questionnaires, and related materials
  - Special subjects
    - Filipinos, 1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 11)
      Correspondence, report, and statement on Filipino immigrant issue
    - Indian, 1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 12)
      Correspondence; memoranda; printed matter; scope of study for committee on methods, agencies, and standards; and statement on Native American children
    - Mexican, 1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 13)
      Correspondence, statement on Mexican immigrant children, and telegram
    - Negro, 1930 and undated. (Folder 57: 14)
      Correspondence, memorandum, minutes of meeting, outline, and summary of report
    - Comments on Negro report, 1930 and undated. (Box-folder 58: 1)
      Includes correspondence, memorandum, notes, report, and statements on African-American children
    - Puerto Rican, 1930 and undated. (Folder 58: 2)
      Correspondence and an article about Puerto Ricans in New York City
- Committee on Illegitimacy--Children Born out of Wedlock, 1928-1931 and undated. (Folder 58: 3)
  Article on illegitimacy, correspondence, note, printed matter, report, and statement on social treatment of unmarried mothers and their children
- Committee on Socially Handicapped--Delinquency, Section IVC-2
  - Biographical information about Miriam Van Waters, correspondence, and miscellany, 1931-1933 and undated (Folder 58: 4)
  - Commonwealth clinic study, 1929-1930. (Folder 58: 5)
    Correspondence, list of delinquent boys accepted by clinic, and related materials
  - Frederick P. Cabot, chairman, 1930-1932 and undated. (Folder 58: 6)
    Includes correspondence; history of the New York State Department of Correction, Division of Probation; list of chairmen of subcommittees; minutes of meeting; outline of school attendance record; schedule for meetings; summary report; and telegram
  - Report to the Committee on Juvenile Delinquency, 1931? (Folder 58: 7)
  - "Juvenile Delinquency: A Summary Memorandum of Available Material on Extent, Causes, Treatment and Prevention" by Katharine F. Lenroot, 1929 (Folder 58: 8)
  - Frederick P. Cabot, chairman, 1929-1930. (Box-folder 59: 1)
    Agenda; correspondence; list of new members and delinquent boys accepted by clinic; progress report, and future plans; minutes of meeting; schedule for Boston meeting; statement; telegram; and related materials
  - Letters of acceptance from individuals invited to serve on the committee, 1929-1930 (Folder 59: 2)
  - Inter-organization meeting on delinquency, 1929. (Folder 59: 3)
    Minutes of different sessions
  - Central office records, 1930-1931. (Folder 59: 4)
    Includes correspondence, list of committee members and chairmen, and outline of the delinquency program
  - Expense records
    - Socially Handicapped--Delinquency, 1929-1932. (Folder 59: 5)
      Includes correspondence and memoranda
    - Special expenses, 1930-1932. (Folder 59: 6)
- Program of annual meetings, conferences, and organizations relating to children, the role of parent and teachers in society, and the social welfare system, 1925-1932 and undated. (Box-folder 60: 1-7)
  Includes article, bulletins, correspondence, pamphlets, printed matter, schedule, and miscellany
- Continuation Committee (Box 61)
  - Letters of acceptance to serve on the committee, 1930-1931 (Folder 61: 1)
  - Minutes of meetings and miscellaneous correspondence, 1931. (Folder 61: 2)
    Includes list of attendees and telegram
- Follow-up conferences
  - Central--Article on National Council of Social Development, correspondence, memoranda, notes, plans for program and publications of White House conference, and statement by Van Rensselaer at conference in Washington, D.C., 1931-1932 and undated (Folder 61: 3)
  - State, county, and city--Follow-up programs, 1931 April - 1931 January (Folder 61: 4-5)
- Follow-up work of the White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1932 August (Folder 61: 6)
- Follow-up conferences--State, county, and city (Box 62)
  - General information, 1931-1933 and undated. (Folder 62: 1-2)
    Correspondence; list of exhibits and governors of the United States; memoranda; minutes of meetings; notes, organization chart of committees and sections; printed matter; schedule of follow-up state and county conferences; and summary of the White House conference and follow-up conferences by states
  - Mrs. R. D. Rood--General information on follow-up conferences, 1931—1932 and undated. (Folder 62: 3)
    Includes clippings, correspondence, itinerary, list of follow-up conferences in Indiana and other states, medical survey, notes, remarks for Republican National Convention, statement of Mrs. Rood's activities, and telegrams
  - Exhibits and publicity, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 62: 4)
    Correspondence, list of exhibits, memoranda, notes, schedule for meetings, and telegrams
  - State of California--Correspondence, 1934-1935. (Folder 62: 5)
    Includes memoranda, organization plan, outline of work, program, summary of the follow-up conference, and telegrams
  - Miscellany, undated. (Folder 62: 6)
    Carbon copies of maps of states
  - "The Role of School in Child Health and Protection,", undated (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Minutes of meetings, Denver, Colorado, 1931 (Folder 63: 2)
  - Juvenile courts
    - San Francisco, 1934-1935. (Folder 63: 3)
      Correspondence, organizational structure, reports, and study
    - Los Angeles, 1930-1933. (Folder 63: 4)
      Report
  - Reports of the Committee on Community Plan for Child Welfare, Children's Council and Subcommittee on State and County Welfare Activities, Community Chest of San Francisco, 1935-1937. (Folder 63: 5)
  - States
    - Delaware, 1932-1942. (Folder 63: 6)
      Conference schedule, printed matter, and report
    - Florida, 1931. (Folder 63: 7)
      Correspondence, printed matter, and telegram
    - Georgia, 1931. (Folder 63: 8)
      Correspondence, telegram, and miscellany
    - Idaho, 1931-1932. (Folder 63: 9)
      Correspondence and report
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1931-1932 and undated. (Box-folder 64: 1)
      Correspondence, list of committee personnel, memorandum, reports of the committees and sections of different subcommittees, and miscellany
    - Indiana
      - State Information, 1931-1933 and undated. (Folder 64: 2)
        Clippings, compilation and follow-up data and plans of the conference, correspondence, memoranda, press release, program, questionnaires, report, schedule of county conferences, and miscellany. Includes 2 photographic prints of different committees, undated
      - Correspondence, 1930-1932. (Folder 64: 3)
        Includes telegrams and printed matter
      - County conferences
        - Adams County, Decatur, 1931 and undated. (Folder 64: 4)
          Brochure, notes, program, and miscellany
        - Allen County, Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1931. (Folder 64: 5)
          Brochure, correspondence, program, and miscellany
        - Carroll County, Delphy, 1931. (Folder 64: 6)
          Correspondence, program, and miscellany
        - Cass County, 1931. (Folder 64: 7)
        - Clark County, Jeffersonville, 1931. (Folder 64: 8)
          Letter
        - Decatur County, Greensburg, undated. (Folder 64: 9)
          Letter of invitation
        - Delaware County, Muncie, 1931 and undated. (Folder 64: 10)
          Correspondence, program, and miscellany,
        - Grant County, Marion, 1931. (Folder 64: 11)
          Correspondence, note, program, and miscellany
        - Hamilton County, Noblesville, 1931. (Folder 64: 12)
          Memoranda, program, telegram, and miscellany
        - Huntington County, Huntington, 1931. (Folder 64: 13)
          Program and miscellany
        - Knox County, Vincennes, 1932. (Folder 64: 14)
        - Lafayette County, Tippecanoe, 1931. (Folder 64: 15)
        - Lake County, Crownpoint, 1931. (Folder 64: 16)
        - Lawrence County, 1932. (Folder 64: 17)
        - Madison County, Anderson, 1930-1931. (Folder 64: 18)
        - Marshall County, Plymouth, 1931. (Folder 64: 19)
          Program
        - Monroe County, Bloomington, 1930-1931. (Folder 64: 20)
          Clippings, correspondence, program, and miscellany
        - Orange County, Poali, undated. (Folder 64: 21)
        - Owen County, Spencer, undated. (Folder 64: 22)
          Note
        - Shelby County, Shelbyville, 1931 and undated. (Folder 64: 23)
          Letter, note, program, report, and miscellany
        - St. Joseph County, South Bend, 1931. (Box-folder 65: 1)
          Clippings, correspondence, lists of committee chairmen and members, program, report, and miscellany
        - Vanderburgh County, Evansville, 1931. (Folder 65: 2)
          Correspondence, program, report, telegram, and miscellany
        - Vigo County, Terre Haute, 1931. (Folder 65: 3)
          Correspondence, printed matter, program, telegram, and miscellany
        - Wabash County, Wabash, 1931 and undated. (Folder 65: 4)
        - Winona, Northern Indiana, 1931 and undated. (Folder 65: 5)
          Correspondence, report, and miscellany
    - Iowa
      - General, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 65: 6)
        Articles by E. H. Cary and George D. Stoddard, bulletins of the State University of Iowa, correspondence, printed matter, proceedings, report, and weekly health message
      - Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 65: 7)
        Includes articles by E. H. Cary; lists of persons registering for Iowa medical conference section, state officers, and residents invited to the November conference; printed matter; and telegram
    - Kansas--Correspondence, 1931-1936 and undated. (Folder 65: 8)
      Includes clippings, lists of residents invited to the November conference and state officers, memoranda, program, report, and telegram
    - United States--Territories and protectorates
      - Cuba, 1930-1932. (Folder 65: 9)
        Correspondence and clipping
      - Philippine Islands, 1931-1932. (Folder 65: 10)
        Correspondence. Includes printed matter and miscellany
      - Puerto Rico, 1929-1931. (Folder 65: 11)
      - Virgin Islands, 1932. (Folder 65: 12)
        Correspondence. Includes clipping and related materials
    - Kentucky (Box 66)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 66: 1-2)
        Includes clipping, lists of individuals attending the conference and state officers, map, population bulletin, printed matter, report, summary of the findings of the health section of the White House conference, telegram, and related materials
      - Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1931-1932. (Folder 66: 3)
      - Bulletin of the Bureau of School Service, lists of committees and county committees, proceedings of Louisville and Jefferson County White House conferences, Kentucky Medical Journal, and schedule, 1932 (Folder 66: 4)
    - Louisiana--Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 66: 5)
      Includes Journal of the Louisiana Teachers Association; lists of conference speakers, residents invited to the November conference, and state officers; note; printed matter; program; and telegram
    - Maine--Correspondence, 1931-1932. (Box-folder 67: 1)
      Includes lists of people registered and staff officers, minutes of meeting, note, program, statistical data, and telegram
    - Maryland--Correspondence, 1931-1933. (Folder 67: 2)
    - Massachusetts
      - Correspondence, 1931-1939 and undated. (Folder 67: 3-4)
        Includes brochure, bulletin, form letter, lists of persons registering for medical conference section and state officers, memoranda, printed matter, statistical data, telegram, and miscellany
      - Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1931-1932. (Folder 67: 5)
        Correspondence, program, and telegram
      - Requests for charters and other conference materials, 1934-1944. (Folder 67: 6)
        Includes correspondence and miscellany
      - State information, 1933 and undated. (Folder 67: 7)
        Bulletin, correspondence, and related materials
    - Michigan
      - Correspondence
        - 1931-1936. (Folder 67: 8)
          Includes lists of persons registered to attend the November conference and medical conferences, printed matter, and telegram
        - 1932 and undated. (Box-folder 68: 1)
          Includes address by Ray Lyman Wilbur, biographical information of Thomas B. Cooley, clippings, press release, printed matter, program, report, and telegram
      - State information file, 1930-1932. (Folder 68: 2)
        Includes bulletin, clippings, list of state officers, Michigan Journal of Physical Education, printed matter, and report
    - Minnesota--Correspondence, 1930-1934 and undated. (Folder 68: 3)
      Includes lists of medical conferences, persons registered for November conference, and state officers; press release; and telegram
    - Mississippi--Correspondence, 1931-1933 and undated. (Folder 68: 4)
      Includes lists of members of Continuation Committee, counties represented in the state, and state officers; minutes of meeting; newsletter; program; schedule; telegram; and miscellany
    - Missouri
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934 and undated. (Folder 68: 5)
        Includes lists of persons registered for the November conference, medical conferences, and state officers; note; outline for a committee report for Health Education and Training and National Negro Health Week; printed matter; telegram; and miscellany
      - May Day Conference proceedings--"Follow Up" program, 1931 (Box-folder 69: 1)
    - Montana--Correspondence, 1931-1934 and undated. (Folder 69: 2)
      Includes lists of persons registered for the November conference, state officers, and state groups involved with child welfare work; map; note; printed matter; program; report; statistical data; and telegram
    - Nebraska--Correspondence, 1931-1934 and undated. (Folder 69: 3)
      Includes clippings; lists of persons registered for the November conference, members of the White House conference, and state officers; memoranda; review of the White House conference; and telegram
    - Nevada--State information, 1930-1932 and undated. (Folder 69: 4)
      Includes correspondence, memoranda, and miscellany
    - New Hampshire--Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 69: 5)
      Includes printed matter, proclamation for Child Health Day, and report
    - New Jersey
      - Miscellany, 1930-1945 and undated. (Folder 69: 6)
        Includes abstract of address by Morgan F. Larson, bulletin, correspondence, list of members of the Continuation Committee, memoranda, printed matter, statistical data, and related materials
      - New Jersey Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1931. (Folder 69: 7)
        Addresses and abstracts of committee reports
      - State information records, 1929-1934 and undated. (Box-folder 70: 1)
        Includes materials relating to "Statistical and Research in the New Jersey Penal and Correctional System" by Emil Frankel, press release, and statistical summary report for the fiscal year
      - Publication, 1931-1932. (Folder 70: 2)
        Correspondence and note
    - New Mexico--Correspondence, 1931-1932. (Folder 70: 3)
      Includes chart, clipping, memoranda, and report
    - New York--Correspondence, 1930-1932 and undated. (Folder 70: 4)
      Includes announcement by Children's Aid Society on radio talk show, booklet about the Committee on Health of the New York Principals Association, clipping, list of residents registered at the November conference, memoranda, monograph, note, printed matter, program, reports, telegram, and miscellany
    - North Carolina--State information, 1931-1932. (Folder 70: 5)
      Includes correspondence and information about North Carolina's cooperative program to interpret and adapt White House conference reports
    - North Dakota--Correspondence., 1931. (Folder 70: 6)
      Includes brochure, clipping, and report
    - Ohio--Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Folder 70: 7)
      Includes clipping, memoranda, note, report, and telegram
    - Ohio--Correspondence, 1931-1932 and undated. (Box-folder 71: 1)
      Includes note, press release, statistical data on Ohio, and telegram
    - Oklahoma
      - Requests for charter and other conference materials, 1933-1939. (Folder 71: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934. (Folder 71: 3)
        Includes brochure; lists of Planning Committee members, participants at the medical conference, persons registered at November conference, and state officers; memoranda; note; printed matter; report; schedule; statistical data on Oklahoma; and telegrams
      - State information, 1928-1942. (Folder 71: 4)
        Brochures, clipping, lists of registrants to November and February conferences and state officers, news and population bulletins, printed matter, program, report, and statistical data. Also includes 4 photographic prints depicting Healthland Flyer exhibits, Bureau of Maternity and Infancy, State Department of Public Health, undated
      - Bulletin1s from the Department of Public Health, 1930-1932 and undated (Folder 71: 5)
    - Oregon
      - Correspondence, 1931-1938. (Folder 71: 6)
        Includes announcement, bulletin, list of Oregon agencies interested in Sections I-IV of the White House conference, memoranda, printed matter, telegram, and miscellany
      - State information, 1931-1935 and undated. (Box-folder 72: 1)
        Bulletin; clippings; correspondence; lists of committees and sections, participants at the medical conferences, and registrants attending the November conference; press release; printed matter; report; and related materials. Includes 3 photographic prints depicting Mrs. Saidie Orr Dunbar and children and nurses at the Infant Welfare Clinics, undated
      - Requests for charter and other conference materials, 1932-1941. (Folder 72: 2)
    - Pennsylvania
      - Requests for charter and other conference materials, 1931-1941. (Folder 72: 3)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1938 and undated. (Folder 72: 4-5)
        Includes lists of registrants at the November and February conferences, state officers, and attendees at the medical conference, and statistical data on Pennsylvania
      - Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1931-1932. (Folder 72: 6)
    - Rhode Island
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934. (Folder 72: 7)
        Includes lists of participants at the medical conference, attendees at the White House conference, and state officers, and memoranda
      - Printed matter, 1920-1931 and undated. (Folder 72: 8)
        Includes address by L. A. Round, clippings, medical inspection records, and statistical data
    - South Carolina
      - Requests for charters and other conference materials, 1934-1942. (Box-folder 73: 1)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934. (Folder 73: 2)
        Includes financial records, note, telegram, and miscellany
      - State information, 1930-1932. (Folder 73: 3)
        Bulletins, clipping, note, printed matter, report, statistical data, and miscellany
    - South Dakota--Correspondence, 1931-1934 and undated. (Folder 73: 4)
      Includes bulletin; clippings; lists of persons registered at November conference, medical conferences, and state officers; printed matter; proclamation for Child Health Day; resume of Mrs. Rood; telegram; and miscellany
    - Tennessee
      - Requests for charters and other conference materials, 1934-1941. (Folder 73: 5)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934 and undated. (Folder 73: 6-7)
        Includes brochures; bulletins; lists of state officers, persons registered at November conference, and names of chairmen of sections at state conferences; memoranda; note; statistical data; telegrams; and related materials
      - Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1931-1932. (Folder 73: 8)
    - Texas (Box 74)
      - Requests for charters and other conference materials, 1934-1941. (Folder 74: 1)
        Correspondence and printed matter
      - Correspondence, 1930-1937. (Folder 74: 2)
        Includes lists of persons registered at the November conference, medical conference, and state officers; note; printed matter; and telegrams
      - Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1930-1932 and undated. (Folder 74: 3)
        Correspondence, note, printed matter, including a copy of The Children's Charter, and report
      - State information--Printed matter, 1933-1937. (Folder 74: 4)
        Includes lists of state officers and persons registered at the November conference, report, and county survey by County Children's Council
    - Utah
      - Requests for charters and other conference materials, 1936-1939. (Folder 74: 5)
      - Reports--White House conference, and health conditions and facilities in Utah, 1931-1936 (Folder 74: 6-7)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1934 and undated. (Box-folder 75: 1)
        Includes addresses; clippings; lists of state officers and persons who attended the November conference; map; printed matter; report of visiting teacher work; summary of the findings and recommendations of the Committee on Vocational Guidance and Training; telegram; and miscellany
    - Vermont
      - Requests for charter and other conference materials, 1935. (Folder 75: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934. (Folder 75: 3)
        Includes list of general and medical conferences and statistical data on Vermont
      - State information, 1930-1932 and undated. (Folder 75: 4)
        Biographical information about Bronson Crothers, clippings, lists of teachers in Windham Central District and persons registered to attend November and February conferences, program, report, and statistical data on Vermont. Includes Rural Vermont: A Program for the Future by Two Hundred Vermonters
    - Virginia